{"tossups": [{"question": "An early scene in a novel centering on these people includes rumors that one of them was murdered with a knitting needle out of jealousy and also mentions one of them poisoning a man with toilet cleaner. Before a celebration in a novel, one of these characters secretly sneaks a piece of butter in her shoe, which she later uses as (*) lotion. These people greet each other with the phrases \u201cblessed be the fruit\u201d and \u201cpraise be.\u201d One of these people sees the bodies of salvaged men on display at \u201cthe Wall,\u201d and is fearful that her husband would be among them. In a novel, Moira escapes from the \u201cRed Center,\u201d where these people are trained. One of these characters sleeps with the chauffeur Nick, who is a member of the Mayday Resistance attempting to overthrow Gilead. Commanders often have children with, for 10 points, what title women in a Margaret Atwood novel?", "answer": "handmaids [accept The Handmaid\u2019s Tale; prompt on women; prompt on Offred, I guess]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>handmaids</u></b> [accept <b><u>The Handmaid\u2019s Tale</u></b>; prompt on <u>women</u>; prompt on <u>Offred, I guess</u>]", "acceptable": ["handmaids", "The Handmaid\u2019s Tale"], "promptable": ["women", "Offred, I guess"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A character in this play is accused of genetically modifying humans to all look like himself. Another character in this play recites a Latin prayer to his wife, who calls him a \u201cfat flop\u201d and says her father will never \u201cpublish this kind of crap\u201d about his work. A character in this play becomes distraught when told her \u201cpuff went away\u201d after getting married, but later shouts that she wants a baby. In this play, a character repeatedly forgets whether another is a (*) math or biology professor. When the crashing of dishes is heard in this play, a character decides to play a final game called \u201cBringing Up Baby\u201d and says that his imaginary son died swerving to avoid a porcupine, leading his wife to dejectedly answer \u201cI am\u201d to the title question. For 10 points, Nick and Honey visit the dysfunctional couple George and Martha in what play by Edward Albee?", "answer": "Who\u2019s Afraid of Virginia Woolf?", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Who\u2019s Afraid of Virginia Woolf?</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Who\u2019s Afraid of Virginia Woolf?"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This novel mentions that a character was \u201cjilted\u201d by her cousin Rutland Whitney, and later chapters describe Ole Benson\u2019s crush on a dressmaker. A man in this novel claims sunflowers were introduced to its setting by Mormons, and when he is returned a worn-out collar, a character in this work fights Ambrosch. In this novel, d\u2019Arnault entertains guests at a hotel while a character tells a terrifying story about wolves attacking a Russian village. In this novel, (*) Wick Cutter attempts to rape the title character before the narrator saves her from a massive rattlesnake. Lena befriends the protagonist of this novel. The beginning of this novel introduces the town of Black Hawk, Nebraska, home to the Shimerda family. For 10 points, name this novel about Jim Burden, penned by Willa Cather.", "answer": "My Anton\u00eda", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>My Anton\u00eda</u></b>", "acceptable": ["My Anton\u00eda"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The narrator of one poem in this book realizes the brevity of life when he considers how \u201cthe Roman\u201d is now \u201cashes under Uricon.\u201d The title figure of a poem in this book has \u201cEyes the shady night has cut\u201d which \u201cCannot see the record cut.\u201d One figure in this collection shows his resistance to poison when \u201cthey poured strychnine in his cup / And shook to see him drink it up.\u201d The speaker of one poem in this collection gets angry at the title character and says, \u201cyou eat your (*) victuals fast enough.\u201d That poem in this collection states that \u201cmalt does more than Milton can / To justify God\u2019s way to man.\u201d The addressee of a poem in this collection is told \u201cearly though the laurel grows / It withers quicker than the rose.\u201d For 10 points, name this collection that includes \u201cTerence, this is Stupid Stuff\u201d and \u201cTo an Athlete Dying Young,\u201d written by A.E. Housman.", "answer": "A Shropshire Lad", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>A Shropshire Lad</u></b>", "acceptable": ["A Shropshire Lad"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This person \u201cthinks on men and kings\u201d because \u201cwhen the sick world cries, how can he sleep?\u201d In that poem about this man, \u201che cannot sleep upon his hillside now\u201d because \u201cit breaks his heart that kings must murder still.\u201d The speaker of a work about this man says that he will combine \u201csea-winds blown from east and west\u201d with the \u201cbreath of [his] chant\u201d to make a \u201cperfume\u201d for him. This man is told to (*) \u201crise up\u201d so he can \u201chear the bells'' and the \u201cbugle trills.\u201d One work eulogizing this man references a \u201cgreat star early droop\u2019d in the western sky in the night.\u201d In one work about this man, he \u201cdoes not answer, his lips are pale and still.\u201d. For 10 points, name this American president memorialized in \u201cWhen Lilacs Last in the Dooryard Bloom\u2019d'' and \u201cO Captain! My Captain!\u201d following his assassination.", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Abraham Lincoln</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Abraham Lincoln"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The \u201cgod of flies and death\u201d approaches this character, calling himself Demetrios. In that play about this character, he travels with his tutor and disguises himself as Philebus. In another play, this character interprets himself as the snake in a dream where a snake bit his mother\u2019s breast as she nursed it. This character is revealed to be hiding when his sister discovers a (*) lock of golden hair on a grave along with identical footprints. Athena casts the tie breaking vote to acquit this character in a trial prosecuted by the Furies, leading them to be renamed to the \u201cEumenides.\u201d This character conspires to murder Aegisthus and Clytemnestra after reuniting with his sister Electra. For 10 points, name this title character of an Aeschylus trilogy.", "answer": "Orestes [accept the Oresteia] (the first two sentences refer to Jean-Paul-Sartre\u2019s The Flies)", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Orestes</u></b> [accept the <b><u>Oresteia</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Orestes", "Oresteia"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "the first two sentences refer to Jean-Paul-Sartre\u2019s The Flies"}, {"question": "Description acceptable. One of these characters tells another to look in a calendar to see if the moon will shine to provide proper lighting for a certain night. Another one of these characters tells that person that he is fit to play \u201ca sweet faced man, a proper man that one shall see in a summer\u2019s day,\u201d but later calls him a \u201cbully.\u201d A monologue given by one of these characters begins (*) \u201cI see their knavery.\u201d During a performance, that character demands to a wall \u201cShow me thy chink to blink through with mine eyne!\u201d After falling out of love with one member of this group, a character declares \u201cMethought I was enamored of an ass!\u201d Peter Quince and the arrogant Nick Bottom are members of, for 10 points, what group that produces the play-within-a-play Pyramus and Thisbe in A Midsummer Night\u2019s Dream?", "answer": "the Rude Mechanicals [generously accept answers describing the acting troupe in A Midsummer Night\u2019s Dream; prompt on \u201ccharacters in a A Midsummer Night\u2019s Dream\u201d; prompt on actors]", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>the Rude Mechanicals</u></b> [generously accept answers describing the acting troupe in A Midsummer Night\u2019s Dream; prompt on <u>\u201ccharacters in a A Midsummer Night\u2019s Dream\u201d</u>; prompt on <u>actors</u>]", "acceptable": ["the Rude Mechanicals"], "promptable": ["\u201ccharacters in a A Midsummer Night\u2019s Dream\u201d", "actors"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This character is taken aback when asked, \u201cAre you happy?\u201d by a girl who is supposedly hit by a car. A man resembling this character is killed in a televised police chase while this character escapes by floating down a river. This man quotes the phrase \u201cTo everything there is a season\u201d from the Book of (*) Ecclesiastes, for which this man is the backup copy of behind Harris of Youngstown. This man murders his boss after he makes a woman cry by quoting \u201cDover Beach.\" This character convinces the former English teacher Faber to help him by ripping pages out of one of the few remaining Bibles. Captain Beatty asks this man to burn down his own house for illegally possessing books. For 10 points, name this \u201cfirefighter,\u201d the protagonist of Fahrenheit 451.", "answer": "Guy Montag [accept either]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Guy Montag</u></b> [accept <b><u>either</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Guy Montag", "either"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The narrator of this essay is startled by the sight of a cat without a tail, later saying that a meal at Ferndean did not compare to the opulent luncheon at a fictional college. The narrator of this essay loses her \u201clittle fish of an idea\u201d after a Beadle chases her off of the lawn. A line from a book supposedly by Mary Carmicheal shocks this essay\u2019s narrator; that line is (*) \u201cChloe liked Olivia.\u201d The narrator contemplates Coleridge\u2019s theory of the androgynous mind in this essay\u2019s final chapter. This essay claims that \u201cIt is fatal for anyone who writes to think of their sex,\u201d and it earlier imagines Judith, a fictional sister of Shakespeare, who commits suicide after being impregnated by a Stage-Manager. The author concludes that five hundred pounds and the title place are what a woman needs to succeed in literature. For 10 points, name this feminist essay by Virginia Woolf.", "answer": "A Room of One\u2019s Own", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>A Room of One\u2019s Own</u></b>", "acceptable": ["A Room of One\u2019s Own"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one poem by this man, he asks \u201cwhy are your libraries full of tears?\u201d before stating \u201cIt occurs to me that I am\u201d the title entity. In another poem by this author, the speaker has memories of \u201cbridges clanking Joes Greasy Sandwiches\u201d while looking at sunflowers. Another of this writer\u2019s poems asks a dead poet, \u201cwhat were you doing down by the (*) watermelons?\u201d That poem ends with the narrator watching \u201cthe boat disappear on the black waters of Lethe\u201d and describes a trip to the title location while filled with thoughts of Walt Whitman. This writer\u2019s most famous poem\u2019s second section repetitively shouts \u201cMoloch\u201d; that poem is dedicated to Carl Solomon. For 10 points, name this poet of \u201cA Supermarket in California\u201d who \u201csaw the best minds of [his] generation destroyed by madness\u201d in his poem \u201cHowl.\u201d", "answer": "(Irwin) Allen Ginsberg", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u></u></b>", "acceptable": [""], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "Irwin"}, {"question": "This character lives another day after a chicken bladder filled with blood bursts in a parody by Friedrich Nicolai. After this character reminisces about the heartbreak of Leonore, he discusses the gardening experience of Count von M, who used to live in this character\u2019s home. A group of aristocrats gossip about this character, causing him to leave Count C.\u2019s dinner party. Wilhelm suggests this character to work for the ambassador, which fails and results in this character returning to (*) Wahlheim. After reading a passage from Ossian, this character asks to borrow Albert\u2019s pistols under the pretense that he will go for a journey. For 10 points, name this character who commits suicide over his unrequited love for Lotte, the subject of a Johann Wolfgang von Goethe novel titled for his \u201cSorrows.\u201d", "answer": "Young Werther [accept The Sorrows of Young Werther]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Young Werther</u></b> [accept <b><u>The Sorrows of Young Werther</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Young Werther", "The Sorrows of Young Werther"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The protagonist of a novel from this country earns his nickname from stealing camels to make enough money for the title vehicle. A character from this country is attacked by a black dog after attempting to steal turnips from a nun, and another nun from a different novel from this country is seen cleaning entrails from a bathtub. That novel features characters such as (*) \u201cYou,\u201d \u201cShe,\u201d and \u201cI.\u201d A character from this country is unaware of his impending execution due to wanting to draw a perfect circle for his signature, and another novel from this country was inspired by a journey that the author took after a false diagnosis of lung cancer. Works such as Rickshaw Boy, The True Story of Ah Q, and Soul Mountain take place in, for 10 points, what country home to authors such as Lao She, Lu Xun, and Gao Xingjian?", "answer": "People\u2019s Republic of China [or Zhongguo]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "People\u2019s Republic of <b><u>China</u></b> [or <b><u>Zhongguo</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["People\u2019s Republic of China", "Zhongguo"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a play by this author, a character says \u201cThe generation of kings has always loved brass,\u201d before telling that man \u201cYou are a king because of me.\u201d That character appears after watching birds tear each other apart in a play by this man. This author wrote about a queen who kills herself when she learns that her son fell on his sword after spitting on his father. The title character of another of this man\u2019s plays is found by (*) Polybus with his ankles staked on a mountainside. In one of his plays, Haemon is distraught at the death of the title character, who sought burial for her dead brother Polynices. This author wrote about a man who answered the Sphinx\u2019s riddle and finds out that his wife, Jocasta, is also his mother. For 10 points, name this author of Antigone and Oedipus Rex.", "answer": "Sophocles", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Sophocles</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Sophocles"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Before the events set in this text, \u201cAll is silent / and calm. / Hushed / and empty is the womb of the sky.\u201d During an event in this text, two characters use mosquitos to test whether other characters are real or made of wood. The earliest known manuscript of this text was created by Francisco Ximenez. A god\u2019s decapitated head spits in a woman\u2019s hand after it is hanged on a tree in this text. In this work, humans are created from mud and wood and wash away in a flood; later, however, they are successfully created from (*) maize and given gifts of morality and women to make them happy. The false god Seven-Macaw is defeated in this text by brothers who later win a ballgame against the Lords of Xibalba. For 10 points, the Hero Twins appear in what text translated from K'iche' to Spanish that recounts the mythology of the Maya?", "answer": "Popol Vuh [or Popol Wuj; accept Book of the People]", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Popol Vuh</u></b> [or <b><u>Popol Wuj</u></b>; accept <b><u>Book of the People</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Popol Vuh", "Popol Wuj", "Book of the People"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This character sees a British admiral executed for failing to kill enough Frenchmen. After that event, this character dines with six deposed kings in Venice. This character murders two monkeys who are seen chasing after women, but is then scolded because the women and monkeys were lovers. This man survives being burned at the stake and is almost cooked by the Oreillones after being mistaken for a (*) Jesuit. This man fights for the Bulgarians after being kicked out of Baron Thunder-ten-tronckh\u2019s castle for kissing the Baron\u2019s daughter. Cacambo accompanies this man in the search for that daughter, Cunegonde; along the way he comes across his former mentor Pangloss, a caricature of Leibniz, who claims we live in \u201cthe best of all worlds.\" For 10 points, name this title character of a Voltaire novella.", "answer": "Candide", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Candide</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Candide"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A character in a story by this author remarks that it is \u201cstrange that they don\u2019t see us\u201d when he passes the Mosquito Inlet. Stray bullets from a man who tries to shoot a dog force the Weary Gentleman Saloon to be boarded up in another story by this author. The main character of another story by this author has a fistfight with Johnnie in a blizzard outside the title establishment. One of this author\u2019s stories opens (*) \u201cnone of them knew the color of the sky.\u201d The gambler stabs a character known as the Swede in one work by this author. Scratchy Wilson chooses not to shoot Jack Potter after seeing Jack\u2019s new wife in another short story by this author. For 10 points, name this American author of \u201cThe Blue Hotel,\u201d \u201cThe Bride Comes to Yellow Sky,\u201d and \u201cThe Open Boat.\u201d", "answer": "Stephen Crane", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Stephen <b><u>Crane</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Stephen Crane"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Description acceptable. A character in a play from this genre throws ten gold pieces offered by his love interest to the ground. That character, nicknamed \u201cHard Luck,\u201d flees after stabbing an assailant in the head. An oil merchant from a play in this genre scams the protagonist into giving him silver. A play in this genre ends with the protagonist paying 300 gold pieces to let his love interest to marry another man. The protagonist of another play in this genre is exiled by his (*) uncle for refusing a marriage offer, and he hides under his lover\u2019s robes when his enemy appears. That protagonist, Tokubei, binds his lover Ohatsu to a tree and uses a razor to commit the title action at the end of a play in this genre, which includes works like The Uprooted Pine. Chikamatsu wrote many \u201clove suicides\u201d in, for 10 points, what Japanese theatrical form that features doll-like characters?", "answer": "bunraku [or ningy\u014d j\u014druri; accept sewamono or domestic plays; accept Japanese puppet theater and equivalents; prompt on \u201clove suicides\u201d until mentioned by asking \u201cwhat theatrical form were they produced in?\u201d]", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>bunraku</u></b> [or <b><u>ningy\u014d j\u014druri</u></b>; accept <b><u>sewamono</u></b> or <b><u>domestic plays</u></b>; accept <b><u>Japanese puppet theater and equivalents</u></b>; prompt on <u>\u201clove suicides\u201d until mentioned by asking \u201cwhat theatrical form were they produced in?\u201d</u>]", "acceptable": ["bunraku", "ningy\u014d j\u014druri", "sewamono", "domestic plays", "Japanese puppet theater and equivalents"], "promptable": ["\u201clove suicides\u201d until mentioned by asking \u201cwhat theatrical form were they produced in?\u201d"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A chapter in this novel begins with the O\u2019Dowd family reading a book of sermons to pass time during an important conflict. In a fight in this novel which takes place at Dr. Swishtail\u2019s school, one character defeats Cuff after the latter steals a letter. At a dinner scene early in this novel, the protagonist almost chokes after another character tricks her into thinking that a chili was a \u201ccool\u201d name. Parts of this novel mention that all characters created are merely (*) puppets, including one who tries to seduce a man named Jos. An important scene in this novel showcases the death of George Osborne and the eventual fate of William Dobbin, who marries Amelia Sedley, a friend of the main anti-heroine. For 10 points, name this novel centering on Becky Sharp, written by William Makepeace Thackeray.", "answer": "Vanity Fair", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Vanity Fair</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Vanity Fair"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The speaker of one poem by this author says \u201cmy tongue is broken / And immediately a subtle fire has run over my skin\u201d when observing a man talking to a woman. This author\u2019s 31st lyric poem was preserved in the treatise On the Sublime by Longinus. The title figure of one of this author\u2019s poems \u201c[billows] in [her] yoked car\u201d to the author after leaving her father\u2019s \u201cgolden house in pity.\u201d Fragments of this author\u2019s poems are translated in the collection (*) If not, Winter, by Anne Carson. This poet wrote of a goddess who is either \u201ciridescent-throned\u201d or \u201ciridescent-minded,\u201d depending on the manuscript. That poem by this author addresses a \u201cdeathless / daughter of Zeus\u201d and is titled \u201cOde to Aphrodite.\u201d For 10 points, name this \u201cTenth Muse,\u201d an ancient Greek poet hailing from the island of Lesbos.", "answer": "Sappho of Lesbos", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Sappho of Lesbos</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Sappho of Lesbos"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One novel by this author opens with Inspector Godfrey investigating the deaths of a teacher and two businessmen. A character in a novel by this author makes a powerful drink out of the Thang\u2019eta plant, attracting tourists to the setting. Prisoners in one novel by this author lead a hunger strike after John Thompson tortures another character. An airplane crash in a novel by this author harms only a donkey in the village of New (*) Ilmorog. Karanja fathers a child with Mumbi after her husband Gikonyo is imprisoned in one novel by this author. At the end of another novel by this author, Munira burns down Wanja\u2019s brothel after seeing Karega enter and leave it. The traitor Mugo admits to killing Kihika in one novel by this author, betraying the Mau Mau Rebellion. For 10 points, name this author who set the novels Petals of Blood and A Grain of Wheat in his native Kenya.", "answer": "Ngugi wa Thiong\u2019o [accept James Ngugi]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Ngugi wa <b><u>Thiong\u2019o</u></b> [accept <b><u>James Ngugi</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Ngugi wa Thiong\u2019o", "James Ngugi"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}